<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TED on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/ted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TED on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 17:36:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – The Filter Bubble – From Human to Algorithmic Gatekeepers</title>
      <link>/2011/05/video-the-filter-bubble-from-human-to-algorithmic-gatekeepers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 17:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/video-the-filter-bubble-from-human-to-algorithmic-gatekeepers/</guid>
      <description>Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}        Web personalization and personalized recommendations are recently gaining more and more interest. Companies like Amazon, Google, Netflix, The New York Times, Facebook, Twitter, &amp;#8230; already personalize their products in different ways. If you take Google&amp;#8217;s search results as an example. Have you ever noticed that a friend of you gets different search results as you do for the same search query?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – The Sixth Sense demonstrates the great abilities of User Interfaces</title>
      <link>/2009/07/ted-talks-pattie-maes-demos-the-sixth-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 09:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/ted-talks-pattie-maes-demos-the-sixth-sense/</guid>
      <description>Image by Larry Johnson via Flickr     Wired.com states in an article (found by ReadWriteWeb) as follows:
 LONG BEACH, California — Students at the MIT Media Lab have developed a wearable computing system that turns any surface into an interactive display screen. The wearer can summon virtual gadgets and internet data at will, then dispel them like smoke when they’re done.
Pattie Maes of the lab’s Fluid Interfaces group said the research is aimed at creating a new digital</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Evan Williams on “How Twitter’s spectacular growth is being driven by unexpected uses”</title>
      <link>/2009/04/video-evan-williams-on-how-twitters-spectacular-growth-is-being-driven-by-unexpected-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 19:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/video-evan-williams-on-how-twitters-spectacular-growth-is-being-driven-by-unexpected-uses/</guid>
      <description> The next video is about twitter&amp;#8217;s growth by the unexpected use of the service. Very intersting video!
This video I found on the gorgeous TED Talks. Enjoy watching.
(via TED)
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} TED Conferences app (textually.org)  Ted 2009 (q-ontech.blogspot.com)  TED conference accepting nominations for TED fellows (boingboing.net)  Curious about Twitter? (nylady.edublogs.org)     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TED Talks – Tim Berners-Lee: The next Web of open, linked data</title>
      <link>/2009/03/ted-talks-tim-berners-lee-the-next-web-of-open-linked-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 10:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/ted-talks-tim-berners-lee-the-next-web-of-open-linked-data/</guid>
      <description>For everybody who is asking: &amp;#8220;What&amp;#8217;s the next step in internet evolution?&amp;#8221; This presentation of Tim Berners-Lee could give you the anser. Linking Data is one of the most exciting initiatives going on right now. Enjoy the presentation!
(via TED)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>