<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Languages on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Languages on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 12:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Robotium – A Testing Framework for Android</title>
      <link>/2011/04/introducing-robotium-a-testing-framework-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/introducing-robotium-a-testing-framework-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Robotium is an open source testing framework for Android applications. It makes it easy to write complex black-box test cases. Test driven development is a methology where tests are written before the actual application.
 Write a testcase
 Watch it failing
 Write the actual source code in you application which enables the test to pass
 Watch the test passing
 Go back to step 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Links of the Week 1, February 2010</title>
      <link>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-1-february-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-1-february-2010/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to post regularly interesting JavaFX links of the past week. Thanks to Jonathan Giles for his great posts on &amp;#8220;Java Desktop Links of the Week&amp;#8221;. The JavaFX links are just taken from Jonathan&amp;#8217;s posts in order to build a little JavaFX news archieve on my own blog and to inform my subscribers on interesting JavaFX news.
Here are the JavaFX Links of the Week 1, February 2010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Tutorial] – Java Online Programming Course</title>
      <link>/2009/10/tutorial-java-online-programming-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 19:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/tutorial-java-online-programming-course/</guid>
      <description>For everybody who likes to learn the Java programming language or who is forced to learn Java I have found a great online tutorial teaching you the essence of Java programming. Specially students should pay attention to this course as it gives a really good introduction to the Java programming language.
The online course can be found here.
Enjoy learning Java and afterwards take a look at JavaFX.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>