<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distance Learning on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/distance-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distance Learning on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 10:17:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/distance-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change</title>
      <link>/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Ein weiterer Artikel mit dem ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), beschäftigt habe, ist: &amp;#8220;Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change&amp;#8221; 1. Die Studie versucht Antworten auf die folgenden Fragen zu finden:
  What is the self-perception of ICT competences among freshmen and is there a change in this self-perception 6 months after entering the university?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses</title>
      <link>/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 09:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses&amp;#8221; 1 beschäftigt. Der Artikel beschäftigt sich mit Methoden, die speziell im e-Learning für den Erwachsenenbereich angewendet werden können. Die steigende Bedeutung der Erwachsenenbildung soll durch verschiedenen, in der Publikation behandelten Strategien, unterstützt werden. Die Ergebnisse der empirischen Studie können für die Entwicklung von adaptiven e-Learning Systemen eingesetzt werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System</title>
      <link>/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System&amp;#8221; [1] beschäftigt. In diesem Artikel beschreiben die Autoren PASS (Peer ASsessment System), einen Prototypen eines Peer Assessment Systems, der im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Information Search and Retrieval&amp;#8221; an der TU Graz zur Beurteilung der Studierendenleistungen eingesetzt wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Change: Mash-Up Personal Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/2009/05/designing-for-change-mash-up-personal-learning-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 08:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/designing-for-change-mash-up-personal-learning-environments/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        In order to describe what this article is about I cite Fridolin Wild, Felix Mödritscher and Stein E. Sigurdarson:
 In this article we first clarify key concepts and assumptions for personalised learning environments. Afterwards, we summarise our critique on the contemporary models for personalised adaptive learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – It is time for a different kind of university</title>
      <link>/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        Kaplan University has produced two interesting and inspiring videos on how e-Learning can be performed in near future.
 It&amp;#8217;s time to use technology to rewrite the rules of education &amp;#8230;
 [youtube e50YBu14j3U]
Here is another one.
[youtube F3nHvkJSNFg]
Besides I have found an interesting article written by George Siemens on How MIT is going to get large lectures off the blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>