<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social network on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/social-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social network on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/social-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NOSQL Summer in Graz Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Today was the kick-off meeting of NOSQL Summer here in Graz, Austria.
 A NOSQL Summer is a network of local reading groups, that will decipher &amp;amp; discuss NOSQL-related articles, from late June to early September 2010. Each group sets its own meeting pace (usually once a week or once every two weeks) and select which papers are up for discussion.
At every cycle, members read the selected paper at home and then meet up for an hour or so to discuss, debate and answer their own questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Media Revolution – Facts and Figures – [video]</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/social-media-revolution-facts-and-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 19:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/social-media-revolution-facts-and-figures/</guid>
      <description>Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}        The following video visualizes some recent social media statistics interestingly. Quite impressing how social media has developed over the last year. Facebook for example has gained 200 million users in just one year. That&amp;#8217;s incredible &amp;#8230;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_oarMXGq3gIlFZ0z5Fm-Ng
(via crowdspring and mashable)
Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}  Socialnomics Revisits &amp;#8216;Social Media Revolution&amp;#8217; (socialtimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Can Stop Facebook Because Nobody Understands Facebook</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/nobody-can-stop-facebook-because-nobody-understands-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 08:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/nobody-can-stop-facebook-because-nobody-understands-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Mashable has just published a post titled &amp;#8220;Nobody Can Stop Facebook Because Nobody Understands Facebook&amp;#8220;. There is an interesting sentence in this post:
 Have the nuances of online privacy become so complex that they’re beyond the comprehension of mere mortals? I’m not saying that Facebook has any intent to cause confusion, but the complexities of the open vs closed debate and the prescriptive vs descriptive nature of the “everybody” setting effectively act to shut down public discourse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Age of Privacy is Over” says Facebook’s CEO Mark Zuckerberg</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-age-of-privacy-is-over-says-facebooks-ceo-mark-zuckerberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-age-of-privacy-is-over-says-facebooks-ceo-mark-zuckerberg/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        On a six-minute interview on stage with TechCrunch founder Michael Arrington Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg states that if he&amp;#8217;d start facebook again all privacy settings by DEFAULT would be PUBLIC. A very interesting approach which leads to the question if people want if all of their data is available publicly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Grippe-Trends jetzt auch für Österreich verfügbar</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 06:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</guid>
      <description>Google Grippe-Trends (Google Flu Trends) ist nun auch in Österreich verfügbar. Auf der extra dafür eingerichteten Website kann man den derzeitigen Verlauf der Grippewelle in Österreich, sowie in viele anderen Staaten verfolgen.
Google bietet auch die Möglichkeit, die zugrunde liegenden Daten für eigene Zwecke herunterzuladen. Für jeden, der sich dafür interessiert, wie das Prinzip dahinter genau funktioniert verweise ich hier auf einen Artikel von Google (Detecting influenza epidemics using search engine query data), der in der Zeitschrift &amp;#8220;Nature&amp;#8221; veröffentlicht wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – It is time for a different kind of university</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        Kaplan University has produced two interesting and inspiring videos on how e-Learning can be performed in near future.
 It&amp;#8217;s time to use technology to rewrite the rules of education &amp;#8230;
 [youtube e50YBu14j3U]
Here is another one.
[youtube F3nHvkJSNFg]
Besides I have found an interesting article written by George Siemens on How MIT is going to get large lectures off the blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meebo – Messenger Mashup</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/meebo-messenger-mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 07:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/meebo-messenger-mashup/</guid>
      <description>Wer hat nicht schon verschiedenste IM Messenger auf seinem Computer installiert? Bei jedem Verbindungsaufbau zum Internet versuchen diese auch einen Teil des Internets für sich zu beanspruchen. Wem das zu stressig ist, bzw. wer möchte, dass all diese IM Dienste irgendwo zentral verwaltet werden können, der sollte sich einmal meebo genauer anschauen. Bei meebo ist es möglich jegliche IM Dienste über eine Website zu verwalten und über diese mittels seiner IM Accounts zu kommunizieren.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>