<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>search engines on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/search-engines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in search engines on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 20:14:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/search-engines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Video Introduction to Web3.0 (The Semantic Web?)</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/a-video-introduction-to-web3-0-the-semantic-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 20:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/a-video-introduction-to-web3-0-the-semantic-web/</guid>
      <description>Today I found a very interesting video discussing the term of the Semantic Web, not only in a technical way. Have a look at the following video:
[vimeo 11529540]
What do you think? Do you think the Semantic Web is going to happen as many people think?
Related articles by Zemanta Web 3.0, The Movie [Video] (techcrunch.com)  Semantics, tagging and Twitter: Web 2.0 Eureka or not? (ml.sun.ac.za)  Semantium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – How fast is Google Chrome?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/video-how-fast-is-google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/video-how-fast-is-google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>These days Google has released a video demonstrating the speed of their new beta Google Chrome browser. The video is made up in a very creative way. I am impressed how Google always finds really interesting ways to promote their products. Specially this one is of really interest:
For everybody who is interested in the making of this video will like the following one too:
(via ReadWriteWeb and Mashable)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Grippe-Trends jetzt auch für Österreich verfügbar</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 06:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</guid>
      <description>Google Grippe-Trends (Google Flu Trends) ist nun auch in Österreich verfügbar. Auf der extra dafür eingerichteten Website kann man den derzeitigen Verlauf der Grippewelle in Österreich, sowie in viele anderen Staaten verfolgen.
Google bietet auch die Möglichkeit, die zugrunde liegenden Daten für eigene Zwecke herunterzuladen. Für jeden, der sich dafür interessiert, wie das Prinzip dahinter genau funktioniert verweise ich hier auf einen Artikel von Google (Detecting influenza epidemics using search engine query data), der in der Zeitschrift &amp;#8220;Nature&amp;#8221; veröffentlicht wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Wave API combined with the Wookie engine and integrated in a Moodle platform</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/06/google-wave-api-combined-with-the-wookie-engine-and-integrated-in-a-moodle-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 09:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/06/google-wave-api-combined-with-the-wookie-engine-and-integrated-in-a-moodle-platform/</guid>
      <description>Everybody who is interesteded in Widget Mash-ups forPersonal Learning Environments (PLEs) should take a look at this article posted on Scott Wilson&amp;#8217;s Workblog. He demonstrates a very nice usage of the Google Wave API in combination with the Wookie engine integrated into a Moodle platform. Here is a part of his blogpost:   I&amp;#8217;ve created a Moodle course that uses some widgets, all of which make use of the Wave Gadget API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Wave – Google’s next killer application?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/google-wave-googles-next-killer-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 09:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/google-wave-googles-next-killer-application/</guid>
      <description>Image by liako via Flickr     Google&amp;#8217;s newest prodcut which was announced at the Google I/O this week is called Google Wave. They build an incredible tool for collaborative work and integrated services like email, instant messenging, collaborative editing, an incredible spell checker which checks the context of words in order to correct spelling. Other really greate features are gadgets like:
 linky: adds links automatically while you type searchy: lets you search the internet through the application and integrate the searched contend into a wave buggy: through buggy you are able to interact with bug tracking software and easily administer bugs  This are just some kind of great tools available in Google Wave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Google Latitude</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</guid>
      <description>Google released a new service called Google Latitude. This service enables you to see the location of your friends, collegues, etc. Here is a nice video explaining how Google Latitute workes:
[youtube Q-Oq-9enE-k]
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} Google launches Latitude tool to help you track friends and family (telegraph.co.uk)  Blinkx adds couch potato mode to video site (news.cnet.com)  What is Google Latitude- a new Social networking tool and how to use it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google’s SEO Starter Guide – How to improve your website</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/googles-seo-starter-guide-how-to-improve-your-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 19:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/googles-seo-starter-guide-how-to-improve-your-site/</guid>
      <description>Brandon Falls from Google Search Quality Team, wrote on the Official Google Webmaster Central Blog the following lines:
 Webmasters often ask us at conferences or in the Webmaster Help Group, &amp;#8220;What are some simple ways that I can improve my website&amp;#8217;s performance in Google?&amp;#8221; There are lots of possible answers to this question, and a wealth of search engine optimization information on the web, so much that it can be intimidating for newer webmasters or those unfamiliar with the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google-Tochter YouTube testet digitale Videoerkennung</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/google-tochter-youtube-testet-digitale-videoerkennung/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/google-tochter-youtube-testet-digitale-videoerkennung/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase  Das von Google übernommene Web2.0 Unterenehmen YouTube testet digitale Videoerkennung. Ziel ist es für jedes Video einen quasi Fingerabdruck zu erstellen um somit eindeutig identifizierbar zu sein. Den Originalartikel gibt es hier!
Einen anderen interessanten Artikel dazu gibt es auf der Website www.digitalnext.de.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/apple-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 13:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/apple-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Hier ein sehr interessantes Video über das neue iPhone von Apple! Viel Spaß damit! Google Maps on iPhone:
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YRNugqEQYS4</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>