<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Herbert Mühlburger on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/herbert-m%C3%BChlburger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Herbert Mühlburger on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:49:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/herbert-m%C3%BChlburger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – 50 Years of EU in the World</title>
      <link>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I have found a very interesting video on YouTube regarding the history of the European Union. Please have a look at it. [youtube sO75ZsvMkc8]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – Europe New and Old?</title>
      <link>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</guid>
      <description>Europe Union New and Old?

The seminars of the European Forum Alpbach have started today. One Seminar that I am attennding is called “Europe Old and New?” held by Fraser Cameron, Senior Adviser, European Policy Centre, Brussels and Gregor Woschnagg, Retired Ambassador, Republic of Austria, Vienna. Today we are briefly discussing the past 50 years of the European Union as well as some present issues for example the Reform Treaty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft</title>
      <link>/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</guid>
      <description>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft, wie sie sich in Zeiten von Web2.0 zeigt, ist eines der spannenden Themen mit dem man sich zur Zeit auseinandersetzen kann.
Wo YouTube, Flickr, last.fm, Wikipedia, StudiVZ, SchuelerVZ, Facebook, … Benutzern die Möglichkeit selbst aktiv das neue Web in einer noch nie dagewesenen Weise zu gestalten, lässt sich erkennen wie groß der Bedarf ist, sich mit anderen Benutzern zu vernetzen. Nicht nur, dass Netzwerke, wie sie sich im StudiVZ bzw.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>