<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networks on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networks on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 11:23:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Large Network Dataset Collection</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2014/07/stanford-large-network-dataset-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 11:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2014/07/stanford-large-network-dataset-collection/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Stanford Large Network Dataset Collection The Stanford Large Network Dataset Collection was published as part of the Stanford Network Analysis Project (SNAP). It consists of an interesting collection of large networks. The aim of SNAP is provide a general purpose network analysis and graph mining library.
The SNAP Collection contains datasets from various domains such as:
 Social networks : online social networks, edges represent interactions between people Networks with ground-truth communities : ground-truth network communities in social and information networks Communication networks : email communication networks with edges representing communication Citation networks : nodes represent papers, edges represent citations Collaboration networks : nodes represent scientists, edges represent collaborations (co-authoring a paper) Web graphs : nodes represent webpages and edges are hyperlinks Amazon networks : nodes represent products and edges link commonly co-purchased products Internet networks : nodes represent computers and edges communication Road networks : nodes represent intersections and edges roads connecting the intersections Autonomous systems : graphs of the internet Signed networks : networks with positive and negative edges (friend/foe, trust/distrust) Location-based online social networks : Social networks with geographic check-ins Wikipedia networks and metadata : Talk, editing and voting data from Wikipedia Twitter and Memetracker : Memetracker phrases, links and 467 million Tweets Online communities : Data from online communities such as Reddit and Flickr Online reviews : Data from online review systems such as BeerAdvocate and Amazon Information cascades : &amp;#8230;  It is definitely worth of having a look at the different datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Science Reading List</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/web-science-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 19:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/web-science-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>I have just added a new site to my this weblog called &amp;#8220;Web Science Reading List&amp;#8220;. This reading list collects a lot of interesting information on web science and similar topics. Since I do not have time to read all of the articles immediately I am going to collect them on this site and bookmark them on delicious too. If you are interested in this topic as well do not hesitate to contact me or to subscribe to my delicious bookmarks and to the feed of this weblog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>