<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video game on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/video-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video game on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 18:06:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/video-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Documentary Explores Indie Game’s Impact</title>
      <link>/2011/03/minecraft-documentary-explores-indie-games-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/minecraft-documentary-explores-indie-games-impact/</guid>
      <description>The impact of indie games given Minecraft as an example is the topic of the following 20 minutes documentary. Wired.com states:
 Of all the videogame industry’s tremendous success stories, Minecraft might very well be the most remarkable. [wired.com]
 Have fun watching the interesting video:
[youtube Ax9kmoyzl1Y]
(via wired.com)
{.zemanta-related-title} Related articles {.zemanta-related-title} Minecraft Documentary Explores Indie Game&amp;#8217;s Impact (wired.com)  Watch 20 Minutes of the Minecraft Documentary (escapistmagazine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Links of the Week 2, February 2010</title>
      <link>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-2-february-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 21:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-2-february-2010/</guid>
      <description>Another week has passed and as I promised last week, I am going to post interesting JavaFX Links here again. I specially want to thank Jonathan Giles, Richard Bair and Jasper Potts for their work in collecting the JavaFX Links of the week. Yet I cannot contribute much to the links of the week but hopefully in the future this will change.
Here are the JavaFX Links of the Week 2, February 2010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wer spielt noch Second Life?</title>
      <link>/2007/06/wer-spielt-noch-second-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2007 15:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/06/wer-spielt-noch-second-life/</guid>
      <description>Hallo alle miteinander!
Ist Second Life ein Hype oder nicht!? Mich würde einmal interessieren, wer von Euch überhaupt Second Life spielt! Spielt ihr Second Life nur wegen GADI oder habt ihr auch schon vorher regelmäßig in der virtuellen Welt “gelebt”? Ich persönlich spiele überhaupt kein Second Life mehr. Den Reiz hat diese “Spiel” schon längst für mich verloren und dieser Ansich bin ich scheinbar nicht alleine, wie dieser Artikel im Standard bekräftigt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>