<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facebook on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facebook on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 17:36:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – The Filter Bubble – From Human to Algorithmic Gatekeepers</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/video-the-filter-bubble-from-human-to-algorithmic-gatekeepers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 17:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/video-the-filter-bubble-from-human-to-algorithmic-gatekeepers/</guid>
      <description>Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}        Web personalization and personalized recommendations are recently gaining more and more interest. Companies like Amazon, Google, Netflix, The New York Times, Facebook, Twitter, &amp;#8230; already personalize their products in different ways. If you take Google&amp;#8217;s search results as an example. Have you ever noticed that a friend of you gets different search results as you do for the same search query?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Drive: The surprising truth about what motivates us</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/09/video-drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 17:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/09/video-drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Have you ever asked yourself if why your employer is not really able to motivate you to love your work? One of the reasons why people are motivated doing what they do is because they see a purpose in their work. This fact you already see in &amp;#8220;Maslov&amp;#8217;s Hierarchy of Needs&amp;#8220;. The following video demonstrates the surprising truth about what drives our motivation.
[youtube u6XAPnuFjJc]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Media Revolution – Facts and Figures – [video]</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/social-media-revolution-facts-and-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 19:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/social-media-revolution-facts-and-figures/</guid>
      <description>Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}        The following video visualizes some recent social media statistics interestingly. Quite impressing how social media has developed over the last year. Facebook for example has gained 200 million users in just one year. That&amp;#8217;s incredible &amp;#8230;
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_oarMXGq3gIlFZ0z5Fm-Ng
(via crowdspring and mashable)
Related articles {.zemanta-related-title}  Socialnomics Revisits &amp;#8216;Social Media Revolution&amp;#8217; (socialtimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody Can Stop Facebook Because Nobody Understands Facebook</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/nobody-can-stop-facebook-because-nobody-understands-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 08:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/nobody-can-stop-facebook-because-nobody-understands-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Mashable has just published a post titled &amp;#8220;Nobody Can Stop Facebook Because Nobody Understands Facebook&amp;#8220;. There is an interesting sentence in this post:
 Have the nuances of online privacy become so complex that they’re beyond the comprehension of mere mortals? I’m not saying that Facebook has any intent to cause confusion, but the complexities of the open vs closed debate and the prescriptive vs descriptive nature of the “everybody” setting effectively act to shut down public discourse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Age of Privacy is Over” says Facebook’s CEO Mark Zuckerberg</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-age-of-privacy-is-over-says-facebooks-ceo-mark-zuckerberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-age-of-privacy-is-over-says-facebooks-ceo-mark-zuckerberg/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        On a six-minute interview on stage with TechCrunch founder Michael Arrington Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg states that if he&amp;#8217;d start facebook again all privacy settings by DEFAULT would be PUBLIC. A very interesting approach which leads to the question if people want if all of their data is available publicly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Rethink the Data Warehouse with Hadoop and Hive</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/video-rethink-the-data-warehouse-with-hadoop-and-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 08:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/video-rethink-the-data-warehouse-with-hadoop-and-hive/</guid>
      <description>Here is a great video explaining how Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive to build Data Warehouses and analyse their huge ammount of data. Every day Facebook gets around 4TB+ of compressed data, which is amazing and also difficult to be analysed.
[vimeo 7111203]
(via Cloudera)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What will the web look like in five years?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 18:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</guid>
      <description>Eric Schmidt, CEO of Google was answering this question in an interesting interview at Gartner Symposium/ITxpo Orlando 2009. ReadWriteWeb has summarized the highlights of Eric&amp;#8217;s interview as follows:
  Five years from now the internet will be dominated by Chinese-language content. Today&amp;#8217;s teenagers are the model of how the web will work in five years &amp;#8211; they jump from app to app to app seamlessly. Five years is a factor of ten in Moore&amp;#8217;s Law, meaning that computers will be capable of far more by that time than they are today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Grippe-Trends jetzt auch für Österreich verfügbar</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 06:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/10/google-grippe-trends-fur-oesterreich-verfuegbar/</guid>
      <description>Google Grippe-Trends (Google Flu Trends) ist nun auch in Österreich verfügbar. Auf der extra dafür eingerichteten Website kann man den derzeitigen Verlauf der Grippewelle in Österreich, sowie in viele anderen Staaten verfolgen.
Google bietet auch die Möglichkeit, die zugrunde liegenden Daten für eigene Zwecke herunterzuladen. Für jeden, der sich dafür interessiert, wie das Prinzip dahinter genau funktioniert verweise ich hier auf einen Artikel von Google (Detecting influenza epidemics using search engine query data), der in der Zeitschrift &amp;#8220;Nature&amp;#8221; veröffentlicht wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Trouble with the Twittersphere</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/video-trouble-with-the-twittersphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 09:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/video-trouble-with-the-twittersphere/</guid>
      <description>            Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        Just found a nice video about twitter and it&amp;#8217;s users called the Twittersphere.
[youtube PN2HAroA12w]
(via blogdrauf.de)
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} Immorality and Twitter  (scientificamerican.com)  Getting sucked into Twittersphere&amp;#8230; (localglobe.blogspot.com)     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Evan Williams on “How Twitter’s spectacular growth is being driven by unexpected uses”</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/04/video-evan-williams-on-how-twitters-spectacular-growth-is-being-driven-by-unexpected-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 19:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/04/video-evan-williams-on-how-twitters-spectacular-growth-is-being-driven-by-unexpected-uses/</guid>
      <description> The next video is about twitter&amp;#8217;s growth by the unexpected use of the service. Very intersting video!
This video I found on the gorgeous TED Talks. Enjoy watching.
(via TED)
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} TED Conferences app (textually.org)  Ted 2009 (q-ontech.blogspot.com)  TED conference accepting nominations for TED fellows (boingboing.net)  Curious about Twitter? (nylady.edublogs.org)     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALARMD – Wecker 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/alarmd-wecker-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 10:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/alarmd-wecker-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Wer schon immer mal von YouTube Videos bzw. von last.fm Playlists geweckt werden wollte, der sollte sich unbedingt ALARMD anschaun! Hier kann man sich seinen Wecker online stellen. Dieser holt sich dann von YouTube bzw. über last.fm und andere Services seine Videos und Musikstreams und spielt diese zur gewünschten Zeit ab! Ich finde die Idee einfach toll und bin komplett begeistert! Sehr coole Sache!
[via Webware]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FBI ermittelt bei Second Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/fbi-ermittelt-bei-second-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/fbi-ermittelt-bei-second-life/</guid>
      <description>Laut diesem Artikel von “WELT ONLINE” machen sich Glücksspieler, die in Second Life spielen möglicherweise strafbar. Das FBI prüft eine Anlage wegen illegalem Glückspiels gegen die Firma Linden Labs. Linden-Lab-Manager Ginsu Yoon antwortete darauf mit einer Einladung an die FBI ermittler. Diese wären eingeladen sich in den virtuellen Casinos umzusehen und zu prüfen, ob diese gegen US-Gesetze verstoßen. Den gesamten Artikel kann man hier nachlesen.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</guid>
      <description>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft, wie sie sich in Zeiten von Web2.0 zeigt, ist eines der spannenden Themen mit dem man sich zur Zeit auseinandersetzen kann.
Wo YouTube, Flickr, last.fm, Wikipedia, StudiVZ, SchuelerVZ, Facebook, … Benutzern die Möglichkeit selbst aktiv das neue Web in einer noch nie dagewesenen Weise zu gestalten, lässt sich erkennen wie groß der Bedarf ist, sich mit anderen Benutzern zu vernetzen. Nicht nur, dass Netzwerke, wie sie sich im StudiVZ bzw.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>