<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YouTube on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in YouTube on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 11:20:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos of Google IO 2011 – Android Tracks of Day Two</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/videos-of-google-io-2011-android-tracks-of-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 11:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/videos-of-google-io-2011-android-tracks-of-day-two/</guid>
      <description>In the next few videos you can seen the recorded tracks of Google&amp;#8217;s IO 2011 Developer Conference covering Android development. Sit back and enjoy! Google I/O 2011: Keynote Day 2 Android Market for Developers Designing and Implementing Android UIs for Phones and Tablets Building Android Apps for Google TV Android Development Tools Taking Android to Work Related articles {.zemanta-related-title} Google TV Gets Android Market And Android 3.1 Honeycomb (slashgear.com)  Google TV will get Android 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos of Google IO 2011 – Android Tracks of Day One</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/videos-of-google-io-2011-android-tracks-of-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 17:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2011/05/videos-of-google-io-2011-android-tracks-of-day-one/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; Google IO is currently taking place in San Francisco and for everybody who could not attend Google live streamed quite some sessions. In the following you can see the videos which are currently published:
Google I/O 2011: Android Keynote Day One  [youtube OxzucwjFEEs]
As an Android developer I am very interested in the Android sessions as you can imagine. So the following the next video first covers advaced topics of android development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What will the web look like in five years?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 18:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</guid>
      <description>Eric Schmidt, CEO of Google was answering this question in an interesting interview at Gartner Symposium/ITxpo Orlando 2009. ReadWriteWeb has summarized the highlights of Eric&amp;#8217;s interview as follows:
  Five years from now the internet will be dominated by Chinese-language content. Today&amp;#8217;s teenagers are the model of how the web will work in five years &amp;#8211; they jump from app to app to app seamlessly. Five years is a factor of ten in Moore&amp;#8217;s Law, meaning that computers will be capable of far more by that time than they are today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Google Latitude</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</guid>
      <description>Google released a new service called Google Latitude. This service enables you to see the location of your friends, collegues, etc. Here is a nice video explaining how Google Latitute workes:
[youtube Q-Oq-9enE-k]
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} Google launches Latitude tool to help you track friends and family (telegraph.co.uk)  Blinkx adds couch potato mode to video site (news.cnet.com)  What is Google Latitude- a new Social networking tool and how to use it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – It is time for a different kind of university</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        Kaplan University has produced two interesting and inspiring videos on how e-Learning can be performed in near future.
 It&amp;#8217;s time to use technology to rewrite the rules of education &amp;#8230;
 [youtube e50YBu14j3U]
Here is another one.
[youtube F3nHvkJSNFg]
Besides I have found an interesting article written by George Siemens on How MIT is going to get large lectures off the blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Matrix for Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-matrix-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 21:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-matrix-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>Just watch and enjoy:
Matrix for Windows
Check out Matrix XP as well.
(via Basic Thinking Blog)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – CNN for Holodeck</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-cnn-for-holodeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 11:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-cnn-for-holodeck/</guid>
      <description>CNN yesterday used holograms for interviews in their broadcast on the presedential election 2008. The journalist Jessica Yellin was beamed from Chicago to the CNN studio, New York where Wolf Blitzer was speaking with her virtual hologram. Very interesting technique which shows where new media is moving.
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x2bRNA2wpYk
(via webstandard.at)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acapella Session</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-acapella-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 17:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-acapella-session/</guid>
      <description>Check out this amazing video wich I have found on Basic Thinking Blog. Don&amp;#8217;t froget to close your mouth after you have seen it.
(via Basic Thinking Blog)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We think</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 11:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2008/11/video-we-think/</guid>
      <description>The following video I have found on e-Learning Blog. Just watch and enjoy, &amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – 50 Years of EU in the World</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I have found a very interesting video on YouTube regarding the history of the European Union. Please have a look at it. [youtube sO75ZsvMkc8]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lasttv.net – Personal Music Channel</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/lasttv-net-personal-music-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 14:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/lasttv-net-personal-music-channel/</guid>
      <description>Die Kombination von Last.fm und YouTube nennt sich Last.tv. Last.tv ist ein peronalisierter Musik Channel, der über das Benutzerprofil (Benutzernamen) von last.fm eine Musik Playlist erstellt und auf YouTube nach passenden Videos sucht und diese abspielt! Sehr interessantes Musik-Video Meshup. Last.fm und YouTube ist eine sehr interessante Kombination!
Auf jeden Fall einen Klick wert!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALARMD – Wecker 2.0</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/alarmd-wecker-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 10:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/alarmd-wecker-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Wer schon immer mal von YouTube Videos bzw. von last.fm Playlists geweckt werden wollte, der sollte sich unbedingt ALARMD anschaun! Hier kann man sich seinen Wecker online stellen. Dieser holt sich dann von YouTube bzw. über last.fm und andere Services seine Videos und Musikstreams und spielt diese zur gewünschten Zeit ab! Ich finde die Idee einfach toll und bin komplett begeistert! Sehr coole Sache!
[via Webware]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google-Tochter YouTube testet digitale Videoerkennung</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/google-tochter-youtube-testet-digitale-videoerkennung/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/06/google-tochter-youtube-testet-digitale-videoerkennung/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase  Das von Google übernommene Web2.0 Unterenehmen YouTube testet digitale Videoerkennung. Ziel ist es für jedes Video einen quasi Fingerabdruck zu erstellen um somit eindeutig identifizierbar zu sein. Den Originalartikel gibt es hier!
Einen anderen interessanten Artikel dazu gibt es auf der Website www.digitalnext.de.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>musicmesh – Cooles Mediameshup</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/05/musicmesh-cooles-mediameshup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 15:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/05/musicmesh-cooles-mediameshup/</guid>
      <description>Für jeden der schon immer mal das Video zu einem Audiotrack sehen wollte sollte sich einmal www.musicmesh.net ansehen. Dort kann man nach beliebigen Musikern suchen und sich danach ihre Songs anhören. Das coole dabei, es wird automatisch ein Musikvideo auf youtube gesucht und abgespielt! Sehr coole Sache!
Metadaten über Musiker, Tracks, Alben, etc… werden per Audioscrobbler Web Services API von www.last.fm bezogen, passende Videos werden wie gesagt über die API von YouTube gesucht und eingebunden!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/die-neue-informationsgesellschaft/</guid>
      <description>Die neue Informationsgesellschaft, wie sie sich in Zeiten von Web2.0 zeigt, ist eines der spannenden Themen mit dem man sich zur Zeit auseinandersetzen kann.
Wo YouTube, Flickr, last.fm, Wikipedia, StudiVZ, SchuelerVZ, Facebook, … Benutzern die Möglichkeit selbst aktiv das neue Web in einer noch nie dagewesenen Weise zu gestalten, lässt sich erkennen wie groß der Bedarf ist, sich mit anderen Benutzern zu vernetzen. Nicht nur, dass Netzwerke, wie sie sich im StudiVZ bzw.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>