<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future of Internet on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/future-of-internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Future of Internet on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 20:43:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/future-of-internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtual Revolution covered by the BBC</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-virtual-revolution-covered-by-the-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 20:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/01/the-virtual-revolution-covered-by-the-bbc/</guid>
      <description>The Virtual Revolution refers to the fact that 20-25% of the word&amp;#8217;s population is using the web by now, while other 80% are yet either not connected to broadband connections or are just not using it, as Sir Tim Berners-Lee, the inventor of the web, states. In Afrika for example, people are now getting connected to broadband internet in a wide variety of areas. This means that the digital revolution that has shaped our world as we know it now, will happen in these areas too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What will the web look like in five years?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 18:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/what-will-the-web-look-like-in-five-years/</guid>
      <description>Eric Schmidt, CEO of Google was answering this question in an interesting interview at Gartner Symposium/ITxpo Orlando 2009. ReadWriteWeb has summarized the highlights of Eric&amp;#8217;s interview as follows:
  Five years from now the internet will be dominated by Chinese-language content. Today&amp;#8217;s teenagers are the model of how the web will work in five years &amp;#8211; they jump from app to app to app seamlessly. Five years is a factor of ten in Moore&amp;#8217;s Law, meaning that computers will be capable of far more by that time than they are today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>