<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graz University of Technology on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/graz-university-of-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graz University of Technology on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/graz-university-of-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NOSQL Summer in Graz Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Today was the kick-off meeting of NOSQL Summer here in Graz, Austria.
 A NOSQL Summer is a network of local reading groups, that will decipher &amp;amp; discuss NOSQL-related articles, from late June to early September 2010. Each group sets its own meeting pace (usually once a week or once every two weeks) and select which papers are up for discussion.
At every cycle, members read the selected paper at home and then meet up for an hour or so to discuss, debate and answer their own questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Ein weiterer Artikel mit dem ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), beschäftigt habe, ist: &amp;#8220;Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change&amp;#8221; 1. Die Studie versucht Antworten auf die folgenden Fragen zu finden:
  What is the self-perception of ICT competences among freshmen and is there a change in this self-perception 6 months after entering the university?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 09:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses&amp;#8221; 1 beschäftigt. Der Artikel beschäftigt sich mit Methoden, die speziell im e-Learning für den Erwachsenenbereich angewendet werden können. Die steigende Bedeutung der Erwachsenenbildung soll durch verschiedenen, in der Publikation behandelten Strategien, unterstützt werden. Die Ergebnisse der empirischen Studie können für die Entwicklung von adaptiven e-Learning Systemen eingesetzt werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System&amp;#8221; [1] beschäftigt. In diesem Artikel beschreiben die Autoren PASS (Peer ASsessment System), einen Prototypen eines Peer Assessment Systems, der im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Information Search and Retrieval&amp;#8221; an der TU Graz zur Beurteilung der Studierendenleistungen eingesetzt wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>