<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 17:53:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Drive: The surprising truth about what motivates us</title>
      <link>/2010/09/video-drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 17:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/09/video-drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Have you ever asked yourself if why your employer is not really able to motivate you to love your work? One of the reasons why people are motivated doing what they do is because they see a purpose in their work. This fact you already see in &amp;#8220;Maslov&amp;#8217;s Hierarchy of Needs&amp;#8220;. The following video demonstrates the surprising truth about what drives our motivation.
[youtube u6XAPnuFjJc]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Internet of Services makes live of young parents easier</title>
      <link>/2009/01/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 11:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/video/</guid>
      <description>Internet of Services makes live of young parents easier  Once a baby is born the organization marathon is just starting for it&amp;#8217;s parents: register the birth, register with the health insurance, apply for parents allowances and arrange a lot of other appointments. SAP Research is developing an internet platform aimed at helping youg parents. Automated Services will connect authorities and service providers with each other by the internet. This saves time and lakework in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 eLearning Articles and White Papers</title>
      <link>/2009/01/100-elearning-articles-and-white-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 11:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/100-elearning-articles-and-white-papers/</guid>
      <description>I have found a great collection of 100 eLearning articles and white papers through dontwasteyourtime. The full list of articles can be found at Dr. Tony Karrer&amp;#8217;s weblog called elearningtech.
(via cristinacost&amp;#8217;s tweet)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Flu Trends – Google Uses Searches to Track Flu’s Spread</title>
      <link>/2008/11/google-flu-trends-google-uses-searches-to-track-flu-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 09:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/google-flu-trends-google-uses-searches-to-track-flu-spread/</guid>
      <description>It stands to reason that people who are &amp;#8220;starting to come down with something&amp;#8221; often take the opportunity to search for information on what ails them, even before they discuss their symptoms with a healthcare professional. Who gets more of those searches than anyone? Google, of course. [ReadWriteWeb]
 Google offers a new service called Google Flu Trends. The service uses an analysis of Google&amp;#8217;s millions of search queries every day to calculate flu trends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>