<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hadoop on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/hadoop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hadoop on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 19:31:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/hadoop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NoSQL Databases: Why, what and when – An Overview on NoSQL Datastores</title>
      <link>/2011/03/nosql-databases-why-what-and-when-an-overview-on-nosql-datastores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 19:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/nosql-databases-why-what-and-when-an-overview-on-nosql-datastores/</guid>
      <description>For everybody interested in NoSQL datastores the following presentation by Lorenzo Alberton is worth reading. It gives a good overview of the currently used technologies in the area of NoSQL and discusses the ground filling basics every NoSQL enthusiast should know.  NoSQL Databases: Why, what and when (via quipo)  &amp;nbsp;
Related Articles NoSQL: Node.js + NoSQL Database = Real Time Chat Applications (themindstorms.blogspot.com)  NoSQL: The NoSQL Gene in SQL Azure Federations (themindstorms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – How is Hadoop used at Twitter?</title>
      <link>/2010/09/video-how-is-hadoop-used-at-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 13:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/09/video-how-is-hadoop-used-at-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase  In the following video Dmitriy Ryaboy, a Twitter Analytics Engineer and a former Cloudera Intern, explains how Twitter uses Hadoop and Pig. Enjoy the video and have a good weekend!
[vimeo 11110059]
Related articles {.zemanta-related-title} How GE uses Hadoop to analyze big data (news.cnet.com)  How GE uses Hadoop to analyze big data (news.cnet.com)  Hadoop There it Was&amp;#8211;Hadoop Summit June 2010 (developer.yahoo.net)  Whooping it up for Hadoop (ycorpblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOSQL Summer in Graz Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Today was the kick-off meeting of NOSQL Summer here in Graz, Austria.
 A NOSQL Summer is a network of local reading groups, that will decipher &amp;amp; discuss NOSQL-related articles, from late June to early September 2010. Each group sets its own meeting pace (usually once a week or once every two weeks) and select which papers are up for discussion.
At every cycle, members read the selected paper at home and then meet up for an hour or so to discuss, debate and answer their own questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – HBase and Pig: The Hadoop Ecosystem at Twitter</title>
      <link>/2010/06/video-hbase-and-pig-the-hadoop-ecosystem-at-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 06:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/06/video-hbase-and-pig-the-hadoop-ecosystem-at-twitter/</guid>
      <description>            Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        I have just found this very interesting video dealing with the implementation of HBase and Pig in combination with Hadoop at Twitter:
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} HBase Digest, March 2010 (sematext.com)  Cassandra+Hadoop (slideshare.net)  Hadoop, Hbase and Hive- Bay area Hadoop User Group (slideshare.net)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter’s use of Cassandra, Hadoop, Pig and HBase for highly distributed Data Processing and Analysis</title>
      <link>/2010/05/twitters-use-of-cassandra-pig-and-hbase-for-highly-distributed-data-processing-and-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 19:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/05/twitters-use-of-cassandra-pig-and-hbase-for-highly-distributed-data-processing-and-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Kevin Weil, Analytics Lead at Twitter recently gave a presentation on Twitter’s use of Cassandra, Pig and HBase. Specially interesting is how Twitter uses Hadoop and Pig in their data analysis process.
[slideshare id=3806196&amp;amp;doc=nosqlattwitter-nosqleu2010-100421124212-phpapp02]
(via @kevinweil)
Another great presentation from Tobias Ivarsson gives an overview on NoSQL:
[slideshare id=3735857&amp;amp;doc=nosqlfordummies-100415085745-phpapp01]
(via @thobe)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Rethink the Data Warehouse with Hadoop and Hive</title>
      <link>/2009/11/video-rethink-the-data-warehouse-with-hadoop-and-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 08:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/11/video-rethink-the-data-warehouse-with-hadoop-and-hive/</guid>
      <description>Here is a great video explaining how Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive to build Data Warehouses and analyse their huge ammount of data. Every day Facebook gets around 4TB+ of compressed data, which is amazing and also difficult to be analysed.
[vimeo 7111203]
(via Cloudera)
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>