<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:49:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – 50 Years of EU in the World</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-50-years-of-eu-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I have found a very interesting video on YouTube regarding the history of the European Union. Please have a look at it. [youtube sO75ZsvMkc8]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – Europe New and Old?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</guid>
      <description>Europe Union New and Old?

The seminars of the European Forum Alpbach have started today. One Seminar that I am attennding is called “Europe Old and New?” held by Fraser Cameron, Senior Adviser, European Policy Centre, Brussels and Gregor Woschnagg, Retired Ambassador, Republic of Austria, Vienna. Today we are briefly discussing the past 50 years of the European Union as well as some present issues for example the Reform Treaty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach/</guid>
      <description>The European Forum Alpbach has started and is going on for the next two weeks. I am really looking forward in participating in different seminars as well as fireside talks.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Life and more …</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/second-life-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 12:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/03/second-life-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Second Life wer kenn das nicht, oder besser gefragt, wer hat nicht schon davon gehört? Interessanterweise haben bei der letzten Vorlesung in einem Hörsaal von ca. 300 &amp;#8211; 400 Studierenden nur 3 &amp;#8211; 4 Studierende angegeben, Second Life zu spielen. Spielen? Second Life spielt man nicht, man lebt in der virtuellen Welt und versucht sich dort in irgendeiner Weise zu verwirklichen. Ob das gelingt ist verschieden. Interessant ist auch, dass die Studierenden von denen hier dei Rede ist nicht einem Studium nachgehen, welches überhaupt nichts mit Informationstechnologie zu tun hat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>