<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>austria on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/austria/</link>
    <description>Recent content in austria on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/austria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NOSQL Summer in Graz Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/nosql-summer-in-graz-kick-off-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Today was the kick-off meeting of NOSQL Summer here in Graz, Austria.
 A NOSQL Summer is a network of local reading groups, that will decipher &amp;amp; discuss NOSQL-related articles, from late June to early September 2010. Each group sets its own meeting pace (usually once a week or once every two weeks) and select which papers are up for discussion.
At every cycle, members read the selected paper at home and then meet up for an hour or so to discuss, debate and answer their own questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper accepted] – Will Personal Learning Environments become ubiquitous through the use of Widgets?</title>
      <link>/2009/05/paper-accepted-will-personal-learning-environments-become-ubiquitous-through-the-use-of-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 18:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/paper-accepted-will-personal-learning-environments-become-ubiquitous-through-the-use-of-widgets/</guid>
      <description>Few time ago we got the review on our paper submitted to the 9th International Conference on Knowledge Management and Knowledge Technologies (I-KNOW &amp;#8217;09). The paper is titled &amp;#8220;Will Personal Learning Environments become ubiquitous through the use of Widgets?&amp;#8221; and was accepted as follows:
 We are pleased to inform you that your paper
Title: Will Personal Learning Environments become ubiquitous through the use of Widgets?
has been accepted for publication as short paper (max.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Flu Trends – Google Uses Searches to Track Flu’s Spread</title>
      <link>/2008/11/google-flu-trends-google-uses-searches-to-track-flu-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 09:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/11/google-flu-trends-google-uses-searches-to-track-flu-spread/</guid>
      <description>It stands to reason that people who are &amp;#8220;starting to come down with something&amp;#8221; often take the opportunity to search for information on what ails them, even before they discuss their symptoms with a healthcare professional. Who gets more of those searches than anyone? Google, of course. [ReadWriteWeb]
 Google offers a new service called Google Flu Trends. The service uses an analysis of Google&amp;#8217;s millions of search queries every day to calculate flu trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach – Europe New and Old?</title>
      <link>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach-europe-new-and-old/</guid>
      <description>Europe Union New and Old?

The seminars of the European Forum Alpbach have started today. One Seminar that I am attennding is called “Europe Old and New?” held by Fraser Cameron, Senior Adviser, European Policy Centre, Brussels and Gregor Woschnagg, Retired Ambassador, Republic of Austria, Vienna. Today we are briefly discussing the past 50 years of the European Union as well as some present issues for example the Reform Treaty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Forum Alpbach</title>
      <link>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/08/european-forum-alpbach/</guid>
      <description>The European Forum Alpbach has started and is going on for the next two weeks. I am really looking forward in participating in different seminars as well as fireside talks.   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>