<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile phone on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/mobile-phone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile phone on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 09:07:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/mobile-phone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – The Sixth Sense demonstrates the great abilities of User Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/07/ted-talks-pattie-maes-demos-the-sixth-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 09:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/07/ted-talks-pattie-maes-demos-the-sixth-sense/</guid>
      <description>Image by Larry Johnson via Flickr     Wired.com states in an article (found by ReadWriteWeb) as follows:
 LONG BEACH, California — Students at the MIT Media Lab have developed a wearable computing system that turns any surface into an interactive display screen. The wearer can summon virtual gadgets and internet data at will, then dispel them like smoke when they’re done.
Pattie Maes of the lab’s Fluid Interfaces group said the research is aimed at creating a new digital</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientist developes a Brain-To-Twitter Interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/04/scientist-developes-a-brain-to-twitter-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 08:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/04/scientist-developes-a-brain-to-twitter-interface/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}           Image via CrunchBase     Adam Wilson, biomedical engineering doctoral student at University of Wisconsin-Madison has developed a brain to computer interface which makes it possible to directly write tweets through thoughts. ReadWriteWeb writes:
 Technically, what Wilson did was come up with an interface combining an Electroencephalogram, or brain wave monitor, with an on screen keyboard for selecting letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – Google Latitude</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 09:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/02/video-google-latitude/</guid>
      <description>Google released a new service called Google Latitude. This service enables you to see the location of your friends, collegues, etc. Here is a nice video explaining how Google Latitute workes:
[youtube Q-Oq-9enE-k]
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} Google launches Latitude tool to help you track friends and family (telegraph.co.uk)  Blinkx adds couch potato mode to video site (news.cnet.com)  What is Google Latitude- a new Social networking tool and how to use it?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>