<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 10:17:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.muehlburger.at/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-information-and-communication-technologies-in-the-life-of-university-freshmen-an-analysis-of-change/</guid>
      <description>Ein weiterer Artikel mit dem ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), beschäftigt habe, ist: &amp;#8220;Information and communication technologies in the life of university freshmen: An analysis of change&amp;#8221; 1. Die Studie versucht Antworten auf die folgenden Fragen zu finden:
  What is the self-perception of ICT competences among freshmen and is there a change in this self-perception 6 months after entering the university?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 09:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-toward-deep-learning-for-adult-students-in-online-courses/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Toward deep learning for adult students in online courses&amp;#8221; 1 beschäftigt. Der Artikel beschäftigt sich mit Methoden, die speziell im e-Learning für den Erwachsenenbereich angewendet werden können. Die steigende Bedeutung der Erwachsenenbildung soll durch verschiedenen, in der Publikation behandelten Strategien, unterstützt werden. Die Ergebnisse der empirischen Studie können für die Entwicklung von adaptiven e-Learning Systemen eingesetzt werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 08:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/05/paper-peer-assessment-system-for-modern-learning-settings-towards-a-flexible-e-assessment-system/</guid>
      <description>Diese Woche habe ich mich im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8220;, abgehalten an der Technischen Universität Graz (TU Graz), mit dem Artikel &amp;#8220;Peer Assessment System for Modern Learning Settings: Towards a Flexible E-Assessment System&amp;#8221; [1] beschäftigt. In diesem Artikel beschreiben die Autoren PASS (Peer ASsessment System), einen Prototypen eines Peer Assessment Systems, der im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Information Search and Retrieval&amp;#8221; an der TU Graz zur Beurteilung der Studierendenleistungen eingesetzt wurde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – TEDxNYED – Dan Meyer presents Impressive Ways to Teach Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/video-tedxnyed-dan-meyer-presents-impressive-ways-to-teach-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 12:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/video-tedxnyed-dan-meyer-presents-impressive-ways-to-teach-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>In the following video Dan Meyer (@ddmeyer) presents an impressive way to teach applied mathematics. I hope that some of our professors will watch this video and keep some of the ideas in mind.
[youtube BlvKWEvKSi8]
(via e-Learning Blog)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[paper] – Learning Management Systems: Are They Knowledge Management Tools?</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/learning-management-systems-are-they-knowledge-management-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 09:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2010/04/learning-management-systems-are-they-knowledge-management-tools/</guid>
      <description>Im Zuge der Lehrveranstaltung &amp;#8220;Technology Enhanced Learning&amp;#8221; an der TU Graz , abgehalten von Dr. Martin Ebner (@mebner) habe ich den Artikel &amp;#8220;Learning Management Systems: Are They Knowledge Management Tools?&amp;#8221; als Leitartikel zum Thema Lern-Management-Systeme (LMS) ausgewählt.
Dieser Artikel beschäftigt sich mit der Frage, ob Lern-Management-Systeme (LMS) zu Wissensmanagement Werkzeugen gezählt werden sollten. Die Autoren definieren zunächst Wissensmanagement und Lernen auf Grundlage vorhandener Literatur, bevor auf eLearning und dort im speziellen auf LMS eingegangen wird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Science Reading List</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/web-science-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 19:18:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/11/web-science-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>I have just added a new site to my this weblog called &amp;#8220;Web Science Reading List&amp;#8220;. This reading list collects a lot of interesting information on web science and similar topics. Since I do not have time to read all of the articles immediately I am going to collect them on this site and bookmark them on delicious too. If you are interested in this topic as well do not hesitate to contact me or to subscribe to my delicious bookmarks and to the feed of this weblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Touchable Holography</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/08/touchable-holography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 16:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/08/touchable-holography/</guid>
      <description>At this years International Conference and Exhibition on Computer Graphics and Interactive Techniques (SIGGRAPH2009) a touchable holography was presented by the University of Tokio. It is a kind of holography that you are able to feel and interact with. Great development that you can see in the following video:
[youtube Y-P1zZAcPuw]
The first page of the presented scientific paper called &amp;#8220;Touchable Holography&amp;#8221; can be downloaded here.
 [via Shinodalab]   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – E-Portfolios for Beginners and the Mahara UK 09 Conference</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/07/video-e-portfolios-for-beginners-and-the-mahara-uk-09-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 09:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/07/video-e-portfolios-for-beginners-and-the-mahara-uk-09-conference/</guid>
      <description>Since few time I am coding an extension to the open-source e-porfolio software Mahara. Therefore I have searched for a video explaining what an e-porfolio stands for and how it can be used:
Here is a video that explains it:
Few time ago Mahara UK 09, the very first conference covering the e-portfolio system Mahara, took place in the United Kingdom. It was organised by the University of London Computer Centre (ULCC) and the University of London Institute of Education (IOE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Change: Mash-Up Personal Learning Environments</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/designing-for-change-mash-up-personal-learning-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 08:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/05/designing-for-change-mash-up-personal-learning-environments/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        In order to describe what this article is about I cite Fridolin Wild, Felix Mödritscher and Stein E. Sigurdarson:
 In this article we first clarify key concepts and assumptions for personalised learning environments. Afterwards, we summarise our critique on the contemporary models for personalised adaptive learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – It is time for a different kind of university</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2009/01/video-it-is-time-for-a-different-kind-of-university/</guid>
      <description>Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title}        Kaplan University has produced two interesting and inspiring videos on how e-Learning can be performed in near future.
 It&amp;#8217;s time to use technology to rewrite the rules of education &amp;#8230;
 [youtube e50YBu14j3U]
Here is another one.
[youtube F3nHvkJSNFg]
Besides I have found an interesting article written by George Siemens on How MIT is going to get large lectures off the blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabelstaplerfahrer Klaus – Der erste Arbeitstag</title>
      <link>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/gabelstaplerfahrer-klaus-der-erste-arbeitstag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 05:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.muehlburger.at/2007/04/gabelstaplerfahrer-klaus-der-erste-arbeitstag/</guid>
      <description>Hier mal ein kleiner Film zum Thema Arbeitsschutz!
Der bekannte deutschsprachige Film “Gabelstaplerfahrer Klaus” sollte jeder der einen Gabelstaplerführerschein macht gesehen haben! Natürlich wollte ich Euch diesen Film nicht vorenthalten! Viel Spaß damit!
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>