<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on DI Herbert Mühlburger</title>
    <link>/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on DI Herbert Mühlburger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 16:32:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Frotendends</title>
      <link>/2018/12/micro-frontends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 16:32:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/micro-frontends/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting talk from Michael Geers on Micro Frontends. He gave the talk at Web Rebells 2018.
   Michael Geers: Micro Frontends - Think Smaller, Avoid the Monolith, ❤️ the Backend | Web Rebels 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming as Performance</title>
      <link>/2016/05/programming-as-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 09:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/programming-as-performance/</guid>
      <description>Programming as Performance? This sounds interesting and indeed it is, as you can see in this video by Sam Aaron (a Post-Doc Researcher at the Cambridge University):
  He wrote Sonic Pi, a program to enable children and others interested in coding and music to create their very individual sounds using a simple keyboard and a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Most Schools Don’t Teach – Programming</title>
      <link>/2013/03/what-most-schools-dont-teach-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 10:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/what-most-schools-dont-teach-programming/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The programmers of tomorrow are the wizards of the future. You are going to look like you have magic power, compared to everybody else.&amp;#8221; Diese Aussage beschreibt den Wert, den &amp;#8220;Coding Skills&amp;#8221; heute und in Zukunft haben. Die Fähigkeit Software nach eigenen Vorstellungen zu entwickeln stellt für jeden Bürger eine wichtige Möglichkeit dar das Grundrecht der Freiheit auszuleben.
Das folgende Video beschreibt was &amp;#8220;die meisten Schulen (noch) nicht lehren&amp;#8221; nämlich Software zu entwickeln und Quellcode lesen zu können.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Robotium – A Testing Framework for Android</title>
      <link>/2011/04/introducing-robotium-a-testing-framework-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/introducing-robotium-a-testing-framework-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia  Robotium is an open source testing framework for Android applications. It makes it easy to write complex black-box test cases. Test driven development is a methology where tests are written before the actual application.
 Write a testcase
 Watch it failing
 Write the actual source code in you application which enables the test to pass
 Watch the test passing
 Go back to step 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google launched In-app Billing on Android Market</title>
      <link>/2011/03/google-launched-in-app-billing-on-android-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 10:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/google-launched-in-app-billing-on-android-market/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Google Android In-App Billing Google yesterday launched In-app Billing on the Android Market. This feature enables developers to publish apps that use in-app Billing and users can make purchages from within the Android apps.
Google writes:
 Android Market In-app Billing is an Android Market service that lets you sell digital content in your applications. You can use the service to sell a wide range of content, including downloadable content such as media files or photos, and virtual content such as game levels or potions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install (Oracle) Sun Java SDK 1.6.x (Java 6) on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/2011/01/how-to-install-oracle-sun-java-sdk-1-6-x-java-6-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 20:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/how-to-install-oracle-sun-java-sdk-1-6-x-java-6-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Dieser Beitrag beschreibt die Installation des Sun Java SDK 1.6.x on Ubuntu (Maverick). The English explanation on how to install Sun Java SDK 1.6.x can be found here.
Canonical-Partner Repositories aktivieren: Dies geschieht unter &amp;#8220;System&amp;#8221; -&amp;gt; &amp;#8220;Systemverwaltung&amp;#8221; -&amp;gt; &amp;#8220;Synaptic Paketverwalung&amp;#8221;. In der Paketverwaltung finden sich die Paketquellen unter dem Menüpunkt &amp;#8220;Einstellungen&amp;#8221;. In den Einstellungen wechselt man auf den Reiter &amp;#8220;Andere Software&amp;#8221; und aktiviert dort &amp;#8220;Canonical-Partner&amp;#8221; bzw. &amp;#8220;Canonical-Partner (Quelltext)&amp;#8221;. Nach dem Klick auf &amp;#8220;Schließen&amp;#8221; werden die Paketlisten neu geladen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Links of the Week 1, February 2010</title>
      <link>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-1-february-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/02/javafx-links-of-the-week-1-february-2010/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to post regularly interesting JavaFX links of the past week. Thanks to Jonathan Giles for his great posts on &amp;#8220;Java Desktop Links of the Week&amp;#8221;. The JavaFX links are just taken from Jonathan&amp;#8217;s posts in order to build a little JavaFX news archieve on my own blog and to inform my subscribers on interesting JavaFX news.
Here are the JavaFX Links of the Week 1, February 2010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is PupSubHubUp?</title>
      <link>/2010/01/what-is-pupsubhubup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 21:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/01/what-is-pupsubhubup/</guid>
      <description>Pubsubhubbub is &amp;#8220;A simple, open, web-hook-based pubsub protocol &amp;amp; open source reference implementation&amp;#8220;. But what does this mean? The following video explains it very well:
[youtube B5kHx0rGkec]
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Tutorial] – Java Online Programming Course</title>
      <link>/2009/10/tutorial-java-online-programming-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 19:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/tutorial-java-online-programming-course/</guid>
      <description>For everybody who likes to learn the Java programming language or who is forced to learn Java I have found a great online tutorial teaching you the essence of Java programming. Specially students should pay attention to this course as it gives a really good introduction to the Java programming language.
The online course can be found here.
Enjoy learning Java and afterwards take a look at JavaFX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[video] – User Interface Fundamentals for Programmers</title>
      <link>/2009/10/video-user-interface-fundamentals-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 08:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/video-user-interface-fundamentals-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have found a great video demonstrating the user interface design fundamentals every programmer should know. Check out the video, it is really interesting!
UI Fundamentals for Programmers by Ryan Singer from ChicagoRuby on Vimeo.
(via Smashing Magazine)
Related articles by Zemanta {.zemanta-related-title} GUI Design by schematic visualization (slideshare.net)  Advances in mouse interface design video (core77.com)  Speaking at EdUI Conference 2009 (xaprb.com)  Visual Decision Making (alistapart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Interface der Zukunft! Unglaublich …</title>
      <link>/2007/04/user-interface-der-zukunft-unglaublich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 05:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2007/04/user-interface-der-zukunft-unglaublich/</guid>
      <description>Hier ein User Interface der Zukunft! Das ist wirklich unglaublich, was uns das zukünftig für greznenlose Möglichkeiten bieten wird! Viel Spaß damit!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>